bmibaby.com 2004-06-04

# www.bmibaby.com - the low cost airline with tiny fares | cheap flights online with bmibaby.com

**booking, security and privacy information**

  * flight bookings 
  * ticket collection and confirmation of booking 
  * credit card security 
  * credit card charges 
  * bmibaby fares 
  * general information 
  * liability 
  * privacy policy 
  * use of cookies 
  * what are cookies 
  * copyright 
  * flight bookings

bmibaby uses a powerful and secure booking system to allow customers to purchase flights direct from our website. This online booking process is very similar to that experienced when you book via a travel agent or through our call centre, but it should be noted that there must be at least three and a half hours between the booking and flight departure in order to process an online purchase.

You can also use the online booking system to check availability and prices and complete your booking or you can call reservations on 0870 264 2229 (01 242 0794 for ROI and + 44 1332 854854 for non-UK areas). Whichever method is chosen, payment can be made using a valid Visa, Mastercard, Amex, Diners Club, Switch or debit card. It is also possible to make a booking using a third party credit card, i.e. a booking using a credit card not belonging to one of the passengers. In such cases the credit card holder’s name and billing address have to be supplied during payment online and at the check-in desk before departure.

Please note that it is not currently possible to make bookings of a specialist nature, e.g. large groups or unaccompanied minors (children aged 14 or under). Bookings can be made for up to 9 people via the bmibaby website or reservations and for bookings of 10 or more people, please contact Group Reservations on 01332 854500. 

**confirmation of booking**

bmibaby operates a ticketless process and therefore no tickets will be sent to you. At check-in you will need to produce acceptable photographic proof of identity for all passengers over 11 years old (e.g. passport, photo driving licence, national identity card, photo travel card, student travel card). If booking via the website, you will be sent an email confirming your flight details and the price paid soon after your booking has been completed. If you have booked via reservations a confirmation letter will be mailed to your postal address. Ensure you bring a copy of this letter or email confirmation with you when checking in.

**credit card security**

To ensure the highest standards of security, the booking system used by bmibaby encrypts information using the industry standard Secure Sockets Layer protocol (SSL). Consequently, bookings can only be made where customers use Netscape 1.22 and above, Internet Explorer 3.0 and above, or any Web browser which supports SSL.

The use of SSL allows all personal information, such as your credit card number, to be encrypted as it travels from your computer to the booking system used by bmibaby. Once received, the information is unencrypted and processed in the same way as a credit card transaction placed via the telephone. At no time is your credit card number stored on our website or in our online database. No more than two bookings using the same credit card can be made in any one day. 

Most browsers will notify you when you have established a secure connection. If you are not sure about this, consult the help section of your browser. If your browser does not support SSL, bmibaby recommends that you update to the latest version.  

**credit card charges**

A 4.00 GBP credit card fee per booking for UK originating flights shall be applied to ALL bookings and 6.50 Euros per booking for non-UK originating flights. 

**bmibaby fares**

Bookings (online or by telephone) must be made at least two hours in advance of travel.

Fares quoted are on a one way basis and are per person. Fares exclude taxes and charges. Fares and taxes may fluctuate due to currency exchange rates and tax changes.

Infants aged under 2 years of age travel free of charge, children aged 2 and over will be charged full fare. However, if more than one infant is travelling on each booking per adult one infant will travel free and the adult fare will apply to other infants on the booking.

An insurance surcharge may apply.

**general information**

All travel remains subject to the general conditions of carriage of bmibaby and such conditions prevail in the event of inconsistency with these rules. 

It is the responsibility of passengers to ensure they have the correct entry, passports and visa documentation, including travel insurance for the travel they are to undertake. Passengers without the correct documentation will be refused carriage with the airline and will not be liable for any compensation. 

bmibaby strongly recommends that all passengers purchase adequate travel insurance prior to commencement of their journey. 

**liability**

A binding contract is not formed until bmi accepts a customer’s offer to buy a ticket. An offer will be deemed to have been accepted by bmibaby once the customer is in receipt of a booking confirmation. Prices are subject to change at any time before acceptance by bmibaby. All flights and products are all offered subject to availability. 

Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event of a genuine website error or inaccuracy, bmibaby reserves the right to withdraw an offer immediately. bmibaby reserves the right to cancel all confirmed bookings that are subject to genuine website error or inaccuracy. In the event of such cancellation bmibaby’s only liability shall be to refund the ticket price paid by the customer. 

**baggage allowances**

You may check in two pieces of baggage with a combined weight of up to 20kgs (subject to our rules and regulations regarding the maximum size of permitted baggage) free of charge, subject to our conditions and limitations, which are available upon request from us or our Authorised Agents and are available at our airport Ticket Desks.  There is no free baggage allowance for infant fares.

You will be required to pay a charge for carriage of baggage in excess of the free baggage allowance at £4.00 or E7.00 per kilo. Carriage of all excess baggage is subject to space availability.

In addition to the list of dangerous items prohibited for carriage in baggage, the UK Department of Transport, Local Gouvernment and Regions (DTLR) has prohibited the following articles from being carried onboard as cabin baggage: 

Toy or replica guns (plastic or metal), catapults, household cutlery, knives with blades of any length, paper knives, razor blades, tradesmens tools, darts, scissors, hypodermic syringes (unless a genuine medical need can be proven), knitting needles, sporting bats, billiard, snooker or pool cues. 

**privacy policy**

As with most companies, bmibaby does use specialised software that references your machine and allows us to analyse the volume and frequency of traffic to and from our website. None of this data is personal in nature and cannot be used to identify individual names or Email addresses. We only use this information for statistical purposes to monitor the areas of the website that are accessed most frequently and to identify any problems with site navigation and overall functionality of the website.

All personal information held by bmibaby in the UK is governed by the UK Data Protection Act. Any changes to this privacy policy will be updated on this page. 

What personal Information is used by bmibaby and why

Online bookings  
On various pages of our website you have the option to provide us with personal information, all of which is kept securely:

We require specific information from you in order to process an airline booking. This information will be used for the purposes of providing you with air transport services. It is possible that such information may be processed outside of Europe. bmibaby may also use this information and disclose it to companies within the British Midland PLC Group for marketing purposes or to provide service benefits. 

If you do not wish your data to be used for purposes other than those relating directly to the provision of air transportation, please inform bmibaby by notifying WebSite Administration at bmibaby, Donington Hall, Castle Donington, Derby DE74 2SB.

Special offers  
On various pages of our site you have the option of providing us with your Email address. This facility is available from the offers section of the site, directly from our home page under the offers heading, and during the booking process. This information is securely stored on our network, and is primarily used to Email special offers and promotions directly to you. We also allow you to enter specific personal information including your name, mailing address, and frequency of travel with bmibaby. This specific information is used to improve the level of service and functionality available online. This information may be shared with companies within the British Midland PLC Group. You can change your personal details or withdraw from our mailing list by contacting WebSite Administration at bmibaby, Donington Hall, Castle Donington, Derby DE74 2SB. 

Links to other websites   
For your convenience and information the bmibaby website provides links to other websites. bmibaby would like to make you aware that these sites may have different security and privacy policies and that we have no control over and take no responsibility for any information submitted to these sites.

All information that is provided during the booking process (including flight details) form part of these terms and conditions. By continuing with this booking you hereby confirm that you have read, understood and accept the aforementioned terms and conditions.  
 ****

**use of cookies**

Certain bmibaby activities such as advertising and research implement the use of cookies. This means that bmibaby may compile statistics about users, information requests, traffic patterns and any other related site information to reputable third parties. However, bmibaby will not provide any information of this nature to any third party that could identify you as an individual. 

**what are cookies?**

A cookie is a small non-executable file that is stored on your hard drive for the purpose of identifying your computer. 

Cookies help us monitor what parts of the site you visit so that we can keep improving our web site in accordance with user preferences. We may incorporate cookie-generated data together with form submitted data to communicate with you in the most appropriate way. Our cookies don't hold any personal or confidential information about you. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off or on your browser however, if you do please be aware that it may reduce the quality of experience we are able to deliver to you. 

**copyright**

Copyright material appears on the site which is our or our Licensor’s property. Do not copy anything on the site without our prior e-mailed or written consent. Except as expressly stated on this website we do not give permission for you to republish, alter, transmit or otherwise copy any material on the site, but you may download information on the site for your own personal use. Except as otherwise expressly permitted under copyright law, no copying, redistribution, retransmission, publication or commercial exploitation of the downloaded material will be permitted without our express permission and that of the copyright owner. 

All bmibaby branded logos on this site are our trade marks. You may not use them without our permission.
